1.5 tailoring.
Previously we have covered the importance
of projects and project management tools
and techniques in delivering benefits to
the organisation and keeping the
organisation up to date, compliant with
legislation and efficient and competitive.
But there is something
else needed too, and
that is a robust project
management methodology.
It may come as a surprise to
many of you and as a shock to
others that the PIMBOR guide
is not a project methodology.
But how can this be you say?
What kind of heresy is this?
It's true.
The PIMBOR guide is not a project
methodology.
In fact, I have been interviewed
for jobs before and have
asked me what sort of project
management methodologies I use.
and I say I use Prince too and they say do
you do any others?
I said yes I do PIMBOC great we use PIMBEC
methodology here but as it said PIMBOC
guide is not a project management
methodology can I prove it easy the PIMBOC
guide itself says on page 28 usually
project managers apply a project
management methodology to their work a
methodology is a system of practices
techniques, procedures and rules used by
those who work in a discipline.
This definition makes it clear that the
guide itself is not a methodology.
So the PIMBOC guide has just said that
it's not a methodology.
You will find that wherever you go to
manage projects, you can't just open the
PIMBock guide and use it as a series of
steps to direct you.
or to set up authorities or
to find phases or stages and
so on, you always need
something else in methodology.
Project management methodologies may be
developed by experts
within the organisation.
They can be purchased from
vendors, obtain from professional
associations or acquired
from government agencies.
Most organisations and
project managers they devise
their own methodology
to work with the binbox.
guide or else they purchase one.
Now I've developed many myself over the
years but I found one that works
particularly well with the pinball guide
is Prince 2 and you know something that's
pretty good about Prince 2 is actually
free.
You don't have to buy Prince 2 whereas if
you look at some of these other
methodologies which are
not as good as Prince 2
and they're asking a big
fact fee just to use them.
You can develop your own as I've done.
They're not going to be
anywhere near as good as
Prince 2 and they'll take
a lot of time and effort.
You're much better off using
something which has been
proven over many, many years
to be a very robust framework.
But the thing about Prince
2 is it does not go into
depth in all the necessary
tools and techniques.
It's a framework, but the PIMBOC guide
does go into all the depth needed and all
the necessary tools and techniques,
but it's not a framework.
So once you pass a PNP
exam, I would recommend
considering studying for
a Princeton certification.
It just makes sense.
But you won't be asked
questions about project
management methodologies on the PMP exam.
The project manager collaborates with the
project team, sponsor, organizational
management to decide upon the appropriate
project management processes, inputs,
tools, techniques, outputs and life cycle
phases to use in the
management of a project.
Take them to consideration the project
environment, the organizational culture,
the stakeholder needs and other factors.
This selection activity is known as
tailoring project management to the project.
And if you're familiar with Prince 2 you
will immediately realise that the
tailoring in PIMBOC is not really a lot to
it not compared with the Prince 2.
And so it's a good chance you will see
something on tailoring in the examination.
The PIMBOC guide says tailoring is
necessary because each project is unique,
not every process tool, technique,
input or output identified in the PIMBOC
guide is required for every project,
tailoring should address the competing
constraints of scope, schedule,
cost, resources, quality and risk.
In addition, consideration of whether the
customer of the project is internal or
external to the organisation may affect
project management tailoring decisions.
Some project management methodologies take
into account the unique nature of project.
and allow tailoring to some extent by the
project manager.
However, the tailoring that is
included in the methodology
may still require additional
tailoring for a given project.
And that brings us to the end of a very
short section on tailoring.
The next lesson in the module is 1.6
project management business documents.
Please read the corresponding chapter of
the PIMBOC guide before watching the video
And as a spoiler, let me just say the
project management business documents are
not the same as project management
documents.
So hopefully that's got your interest up a
bit.